eil.com 2018-07-31

# eil.com - Terms and Conditions

**_Our Pricing Policy_**

The base currency on our site is UK Sterling. You can view prices in other c-urrencies by selecting from the list of currencies displayed. Prices in other currencies are approximate and for guidance only. We reserve the right to amend prices without notice. All items are listed subject to availability and include UK vat where applicable.

**_Payment Options_**

We accept all major credit and debit cards.  
If you select to pay with Skrill, you can choose to pay with a card type exclusive to the country you reside in and you will be charged in your local currency. We also accept payment by Paypal, UK cheques & UK Postal Orders in Sterling only.

**_Stock Availability & 'Request Next Available Copy'_**

You can 'request next available copy' where indicated. You will be directed to complete the checkout process so that we can obtain your contact details. No payment is required for 'request next' items. If we locate the item in future, or a very similar copy, we will contact you and give you the opportunity to purchase the item. You are under no obligation to purchase at a future date. Stock is subject to availability. By its very nature, rare and out of print items are generally only held as single items. Our site is live and updates stock availability as items are added and sold. Orders are filled on a first come first served basis.

**_Our Delivery Aims_**

All orders are despatched within 24 hours Monday to Friday, or 48 hours over a weekend. We will email to confirm despatch and provide a tracking number only if you have selected to pay for a tracking service. Delivery times vary from destination to destination; contact us if you need specific information.

**_Your Right to Cancel Your Order_**

You can cancel your order within seven days from the time payment is completed. You must write, fax or email and obtain confirmation that your order has been cancelled. If the order has already been despatched, then we will advise how you may return it to us or read about 'Returning an Item'.

**_Returning an Item_**

If you need to return an item to us, you should contact us for a returns authorisation. We will advise how best to return it. Returns will only be accepted if received within 28 days from the date of delivery. You must take reasonable care to ensure that an item is repackaged so that it arrives back in the same condition it was despatched. We cannot take responsibility for damage to insufficiently repackaged items, or items that have been used or badly handled before being returned. We may only refund postage, when approved, for the use of standard mail services. Your parcel must be accompanied by a copy of our returns authorisation email, your invoice or a covering letter containing your order information. Returns should be made only to the address shown on your invoice.

**_Non Delivery_**

Unless UK next day delivery is chosen, we will ask you to wait a reasonable amount of time for your parcel to arrive. This will vary depending on your destination but typically Royal Mail requires that 28 days be allowed for delivery. It is rare in our experience that items go missing entirely, but occasionally they are delayed by a few days. If your order has not arrived after 28 days we will discuss a replacement, store credit or refund with you and arrange this without further delay.

**_How To Contact Us_**

To contact us, click here.

**_100% Satisfaction Guaranteed_**

We are proud of the exceptional service that our team offer and we want you to be 100% satisfied with the service we provide. If you are not totally happy with the order, or the quality of service you receive, please contact our sales team immediately, providing your contact details.

back to top

**_Privacy Policy_**

We respect the privacy rights of our visitors and recognise the importance of protecting the information collected about them. This privacy policy is about how we collect, store, and use the personal information that you provide to us.

This privacy policy explains:

  * Ownership Of This Website
  * The Esprit Group of Companies
  * Our websites
  * Our Partners
  * What Personal Information Do We Collect From You and How?
  * What Are Cookies And Our Cookie Policy
  * How Your Information May Be Used
  * Legitimate Interest
  * Marketing Opt-In And Opt-Out Provision
  * Who We Will Share Your Personal Information With
  * Where We Process Your Personal Information
  * How You Can Access Your Personal Information And Keep It Up To Date
  * Safeguarding Your Personal Information
  * Why We Link To Other Websites
  * Our partnership with Trustpilot
  * Testimonials
  * Mobile services
  * Social networks
  * Where And How To Ask Questions Or Contact Us About This Policy

If you are under 16, you must inform a parent or guardian about our privacy policy to obtain their agreement to the privacy policy before registering, subscribing or placing an order with us.

**_Ownership Of This Website_**

This website is owned and run by Esprit International Limited, referred to as "the Esprit Group of Companies"

**_The Esprit Group of Companies_**

Includes:

Esprit International Limited (eil.com)  
991.com Limited  
Press to Play Limited

And we will from time to time refer to it as "we". 

**_Our websites_**

Eil.com  
Blog.eil.com  
991.com  
Sleevenotes.991.com  
CDswanted.com

**_Our Partners_**

Includes:

Art Vinyl  
Federal Express (Fed Ex)  
Royal Mail  
Parcelforce  
Amazon  
Ebay  
Musicstack  
Rakuten  
CDandLP  
Trustpilot  
WordPress  
Mailchimp  
Payment providers: Paypal, Skrill, Pay360

**_What Personal Information Do We Collect From You and How?_**

The information we collect and hold about you may include your name, email address, phone and mobile phone numbers, home address, shipping and payment card billing address, payment card details, IP address, search criteria, shopping history, shopping preferences, music, film and book interests, sizing's, responses to research panels and surveys, the type of browser you use (a browser is the program you use to look at websites, such as Internet Explorer, Chrome, Microsoft Edge, Firefox or Safari), the times when you access the site and for how long, your referring URL (the site you come from to reach our website), cell IDs (these are the unique identifiers of the telecommunications towers being used by your mobile phone when you use our locations-based services on your mobile phone or tablet) and other location information (for example, GPS measurements), photographs and other content you share with us when you use our services, date of birth, password details, answers to security questions and any other information you may give us.

When you shop with us, there are different ways we gather information about you and covers any of the following situations:

  * When you register with us or subscribe to our newsletters or emails, we ask for information such as your name, e-mail address, delivery address, contact details and, if you place an order, your debit or credit card details will be linked to our database via a tokenised system. We keep a record of this information. All this is necessary for us to recognise you as a registered customer and to fulfil the orders you place with us. Storing this information means you do not need to re-enter these details each time you shop
  * We keep a record of your purchases with us, which means we can create lists of your favourite items to make your shopping experience quicker and more convenient. It also means we can deal a lot quicker with any problems you may experience with your order
  * We keep a record of any e-mail correspondence you send us. This helps us keep track of your likes and dislikes and any problems or concerns you've had with our products or services
  * Telephone calls made to our Customer Service Helpline may be recorded for monitoring and quality control purposes. If this is the case, you be made aware of this at the start of the call
  * Our online chat is recorded for monitoring and quality control purposes
  * Purchase of gift vouchers
  * Interaction with us in any other way, such as via social media
  * Clicking on an advert that we put on our or someone else's website
  * Use our Personal Shopping services
  * Ask for information or assistance
  * Provision of testimonials or other feedback
  * Commenting on any blogs or articles featured in our services
  * Attendance to any events that we run or sponsor, enter competitions or special promotions
  * Signing up for our special offers or other updates
  * Participate in research panels or fill in surveys

By registering, subscribing or using our services, you consent to the use of your personal data in line with this policy. We may also receive information about you from our Group and from third parties, with whom we have a business relationship.

We may record or monitor calls that you receive from us or make to us. We will advise you of this at the start of any call. We may do this for security and training purposes, and to improve the services we provide to you.

back to top

We and our business partners collect information about your use of our online services using cookies. Cookies are very small files that are sent by us to your computer or other device which we can access when you visit our site in future. Cookies help us remember who you are and other information about your visits. They can help display the information on a website in a way that matches your interests. Most major websites use cookies.

Some cookies on this site are essential, and the web site won't work as expected without them. For example without the temporary cookies we use you would not be able to add items to your basket and make a purchase. We give you the option to choose if you would like to have your customer ID remembered to make it easier for you to place an order (we do not recommend setting the "Remember Me" option on if you are using a shared computer/internet access device). This information also enables us to show you products by your favourite artists when you visit the web site.

Every now and again, we may ask you for your opinion on our services and the products you have purchased through our services. When we do research or surveys, we may use cookies and may combine the information collected by those cookies with your answers.

**What is a cookie and what does it do?**

A cookie is a small file that is sent to the browser and saved on your device when you visit a website like www.stellamccartney.com ("the website"). Cookies allow the site to function efficiently and improve its services, in addition to providing information to the site owner for statistical or advertising purposes, primarily to personalize your navigation experience by remembering your preferences (for example, remembering the language and currency you set, in order to recognize you at the next visit, etc.)

**Which cookies do we use and why?**

Our website uses various types of first party cookies (organised and managed by the Esprit Group Of Companies), and third party cookies (organised and managed by third parties based on their own individual privacy policies and not under the control of the Esprit Group Of Companies) and similar technologies, each of which has a specific function. Below is a table explaining them.

**Types of cookie**

**Navigation Cookie**

From the first access these cookies allow the website to function correctly and allow you to view content on your device by recognizing the language and market of the country from which you've chosen to connect. If you are a registered user, they will allow you to be recognized and to access the services offered from the dedicated areas. Navigation cookies are technical cookies and are needed for the functioning of the website.

Functional cookies | These cookies allow, based on your express request, for you to be recognized when you subsequently access the website, so that you do not have to enter your information each time (for example: "Remember me"). If you have added items into your Shopping Bag and closed the session without completing the purchase and without eliminating those items, these cookies allow you to continue the shopping experience the next time you access the website (within a limited period), finding the same articles that were selected. Functional cookies are not essential to the functioning of the website, but rather improve navigation quality and experience.  
---|---  
Analytical cookies | These first party cookies are the property of the Esprit Group Of Companies (the site manager) and are used to collect data in an anonymous and aggregate way. These cookies are used to prepare statistical analyses on the navigation methods of our website's users. The Esprit Group Of Companies treats the results of these analyses anonymously and exclusively for statistical purposes only.  
Our own and third party marketing and profiling cookies | These cookies are aimed at creating user-related profiles to send commercial messages that meet the preferences shown during the visit, or to improve your navigation experience: while you navigate on our website, these cookies are useful for showing you products of interest to you or which are similar to those you have viewed. Third party cookies are those that have been sent by our trusted third party companies. These cookies allow you to be provided with our commercial offering on other affiliated websites (retargeting). With third party cookies we do not have control of the information provided by the cookie and we do not have access to this data. This information is entirely controlled by third party cookies as described in the respective policy. To find out more about the aforementioned third parties cookie, you can inform yourself on their respective polices and knowingly manage your consent or refusal, for this we invite you to visit http://youronlinechoices.com.  
Social Network Cookies | These cookies are necessary to allow your social account to interact with our website. For example, they are used to express your appreciation and to share it with your social networking friends. The social network cookies are not needed for navigation. For more information on the policies regarding the use of social network cookies, it is possible to consult the respective privacy and cookies policies:

[YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines](https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines)  
  
**_How Your Information May Be Used_**

Whenever you give us your personal information we will use it in accordance with applicable privacy laws and for the purposes set out in this policy, on the data entry forms you complete, in any relevant terms and conditions and on pages or emails which link to the data entry forms.

When you use our services, register for or attend one of our events, set up, look at or change your account details or contact your personal shopper or a member of our Customer Care team, we will record your personal details. Your information will be used in the first place to provide the products, services or information you have asked for and to provide you with a personalized shopping experience. We keep the information you provide and may use it for several purposes, including: (i) accounting, billing, reporting and audit; (ii) credit checking or screening; (iii) authentication and identity checks; (iv) credit, debit or other payment card verification and screening; (v) debt collection; (vi) safety, security, training, administrative and legal purposes; (vii) data matching and dedupe, statistical and market analysis, and marketing information; (viii) advertising and marketing for us, our Group and third parties or partners; (ix) developing, testing and maintaining systems; (x) studies, research and development; (xi) customer surveys; (xii) customer care and to help us in any future dealings with you, for example by identifying your requirements and preferences; (xiii) where required by law or in connection with legal proceeding or disputes; and (iv) any other uses set out in the terms and conditions for use of our services. For these purposes we may disclose your information to one or more of the other organisations listed in the section called "who we will share your personal information with".

We may also use your personal information to send you marketing updates, as detailed in the next section.

When you use a credit or debit card to pay for goods, your full card details are not saved by us, but are linked to our payment provider via a secure tokenised system.

Saved payment card details will only be shared with our payment partner and not with any other third parties and will only be used to process your order, using our payment partner's systems.

**Tracking how our online services are used**

We collect, and use third parties to collect and share with us, information from lots of visitors to our online services and analyse it to build up a picture of how people use our websites. This helps us improve the services we offer. We may also give anonymous statistics about visitors to other, reputable organisations, but the information we provide will not include details that would allow these organisations to identify you. For more information on our use of cookies, please read our cookie policy here.

**Customization of our online services and advert targeting:**

We may use the information you give us about yourself and the information we collect via cookies when you use our online services to build up a picture of your interests. We may then use this information to try to make sure that when we send you marketing communications and when you visit our websites or use our online services, you don't miss offers and information that might interest you. This information may also be used by third party advertising agencies and networks, to advertise our own or third party products and services to you when you visit third party websites and online services. This is called advert targeting or interest-based advertising. For more information on how to reject targeted advertising or interest-based advertising cookies please read our cookie policy.

**Data Controller**

The use of cookies by the Esprit Group of Companies, whose registered office is c/o Nash Harvey, Hermitage Court, Hermitage Lane, Maidstone Kent ME16 9NT, falls under the Manager's privacy policy, in conformity with the terms of Legislative Decree 196/03 of the Personal Data Protection Code (Privacy Code) and the Order of 8 May 2014, "Identification of the simplified procedures for providing information and getting consent for the use of cookies" from the Data Protection Authority. Pursuant to Art. 13 of the Privacy Code, we inform you that the Esprit Group Of Companies, as Data Controller, acts in conformity with the terms of the corresponding legislation.

**Acceptance Procedures**

As specified in the brief notice indicated in the banner, you may give your consent to the use of cookies simply by clicking on the "OK" key, and closing the banner with the "X" key, scrolling down the page or clicking on any element of the content within the site's pages. Continuing to navigate upon exiting this cookie policy without specifically choosing to manage permissions is equivalent to granting consent to the use of all cookies.

**How can I disable cookies and manage my preferences?**

Browser The majority of browsers are configured to accept, control or potentially disable cookies through the settings. We nevertheless remind you that disabling navigation or functional cookies may affect the functioning of the website and/or limit the service we offer. Below is the procedure to follow to manage cookies for the following browsers:  
Microsoft IE: [Delete and manage cookies](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
Microsoft Edge: [Microsoft Edge, browsing data, and privacy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy)  
Safari: [Safari for macOS Sierra: Manage cookies and website data using Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US)  
Chrome: [Clear, enable, and manage cookies in Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=fr&hlrm=en)  
Firefox: [Enable and disable cookies that websites use to track your preferences](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)

**Third Parties**

For more information on cookies and to manage your preferences for third party profiling cookies, please go to http://www.youronlinechoices.com. Once on the site, by accessing the area "Your Choices" you can: visualise the list of third party companies, our partners, which install cookies on our site (Company); verify the presence and activation status of installed cookies (Status) and manage your consent selectively (On/Off). By expanding the dedicated voice (Info) for each company, you can access more information relative to the company and, via a link, reach the specific information about privacy and cookies.

**Access to Data and Customer Care**

You may freely and at any time exercise all of your rights pursuant to Art. 7 of the Privacy Code, or receive assistance and explanations on how to provide your consent or selective refusal, or on how to delete cookies from your browser, by sending an email to Customer Care, selecting "Privacy" as the topic. We will reply to you promptly.

If you have any questions or concerns please contact our Technical Team here [Technical Enquiries](mailto:technicalenquiries@eil.com).

**_Legitimate Interest_**

All the information we collect via our websites or through correspondence with you is used by members of the the Esprit Group of Companies to operate and improve the service we offer you. The Esprit Group of Companies processes personal information for certain legitimate business purposes which include some of the following 

  * Where processing enables us to enhance, modify, personalise or otherwise improve our services / communications for the benefit of our customers
  * To identify and prevent fraud
  * To enhance the security of our network and information systems
  * To better understand how people interact with our websites
  * To provide postal communications which we think will be of interest to you
  * To determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising
  * To provide a seamless service across multiple platforms such as email, mobile, tablet & desktop and across social media
  * To provide email communications which we think will be of interest to you
  * Dealing with orders and accounts for the supply of our goods and services.
  * Monitoring and improving any of our web sites and our services.
  * Planning and managing our business activities, including analysing customers' shopping habits and preferences.
  * Enabling third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.
  * Conducting market research including statistical analysis of customer behaviour that we may disclose to third parties in depersonalised, aggregated form.
  * Providing you with information about the products and services we offer.
  * Providing you with periodic communications (this may be by post, telephone, SMS, email or as part of your delivery) about features, products, services, events, promotions and special offers. Such communications from the Esprit Group Of Companies might include advertising for or offers from third parties (which we will pass on, on our partner's behalf. We will never pass your information outside of the Esprit Group of Companies for marketing purposes).
  * Assessing your request for delivery of orders from us where we may make enquiries about you including searching your records held by organisations like Experian and Equifax and credit reference agencies. We may also check your details held by the IMRG Security Alert scheme and other fraud prevention schemes.
  * Enabling a debt collection agency to collect payment from you should that be necessary.
  * Preventing and detecting fraud or abuses of our website.
  * Allowing us to comply with any requirements imposed on us by law or court order.

Whenever we process data for these purposes we will ensure that we always keep your Personal Data rights in high regard and take account of these rights

You have the right to object to this processing; if you wish to do so please click contact us on +44 1474 815010 or by email at [sales@eil.com](mailto:sales@eil.com)

Please bear in mind that if you object this may affect our ability to carry out tasks above for your benefit.

It has always been our policy never to sell or share our data to third parties.

By opening an account with us you agree to us collecting and using your information in this way.

**_Marketing Opt-In And Opt-Out Provision_**

Marketing communications you subscribe to will only be sent by the Esprit Group of Companies. We offer you the chance to receive news, record and music updates which, depending on your preferences, we will discuss with you by phone or live chat or send to you via email, SMS and/or direct mail. These include alerts for new products, features, enhancements, special offers, upgrade opportunities, contests, events of interest, and one-off marketing promotions. You can opt-out of receiving these updates, if you wish. You have the right to ask us not to use your personal information for marketing. At all times, we will offer you the opportunity to unsubscribe from any service or update to which you have subscribed, if you change your mind. Whenever you receive direct marketing from us, we will tell you how to unsubscribe. Alternatively, you can change your marketing preferences by logging into My Account. To opt out of direct mail, please contact our Customer Care team: on +44 1474 815010 or by email at [sales@eil.com](mailto:sales@eil.com).  
If you tell us that you do not want to receive direct marketing, we will still contact you in order to provide you with products and services you request and for administration purposes.

We will share your information with other companies in our Group, who may use it for their own business purposes, as set out in their privacy policy. These purposes may include financial reporting and analysis, strategic planning, the development of customer segmentation and metrics to provide a consistent view of our customer base, research and analytics, to help us source the right products in future and make better product recommendations, more effective targeting of our marketing campaigns, the creation of inspiring content and editorial features, the development of new products and collaboration opportunities with designer brands. It will also be used to provide more tailored marketing by phone, post, email, SMS or any other means (electronic or otherwise) and you expressly agree to such use. From time to time, we may engage third party business partners to provide information about you or to collect personal information on our behalf. We may pass your information onto one or more of the following organisations: (i) data processing companies, mailing houses and other third party suppliers working on our Group's behalf; (ii) ad-serving agencies and other advertising intermediaries; (iii) credit reference or fraud prevention agencies, which may keep a record of that information; (iv) research students, universities and other research and development organisations; (v) regulatory bodies, government and enforcement agencies, such as the police. Every now and again, we receive requests for information from government departments, the police and other enforcement agencies. If this happens, and there is a proper legal basis for providing your personal information, we will provide it to the organisation asking for it. We collate information about site traffic, sales, wish lists, and other commercial information which we may pass onto third parties, but this information does not include any details which can identify you personally.

**_Where We Process Your Personal Information_**

When we use your information as described in this policy, this may involve sending your information outside the European Economic Area (EEA). When we do this, we make sure that appropriate steps are taken to protect your personal information and your rights. By providing us with your personal information, you agree that we may transfer, store and process your information outside the EEA. Governments in certain countries such as the USA have broad powers to access data for security, crime prevention and detection and law enforcement purposes.

**_How You Can Access Your Personal Information And Keep It Up To Date_**

You have the right to see information we hold about you, with some exceptions which are described in the privacy laws. If you would like a copy of your personal information, please contact our privacy officer at [sales@eil.com](mailto:sales@eil.com) You will need to pay a processing fee.

You have the right to review and update your personal details. If for any reason you are concerned that the personal information we hold is not correct, please visit our online services and, after logging into the site using the "Sign In" menu on the home page, your personal information will be made available for review and change in the "My Account" section. Only you or, upon your request, our Customer Care team, may access your personal data from our online services using your user ID and password. Information may be changed online within "My Details", "Shipping Details" and "My Email Preferences".

You can change saved credit/debit card details only when a purchase is made. To delete a credit card please emails us at [sales@eil.com](mailto:sales@eil.com)

If you change your billing or shipping address while your order is still being processed, the order will be re-processed through security validation checks. If you prefer, you may contact us by email at [sales@eil.com](mailto:sales@eil.com) and we will amend your personal details.

Our Live Chat provider records all chat conversations. To receive a copy of your chat conversation simply request this when exiting Live Chat

**_Safeguarding Your Personal Information_**

We will take reasonable care to maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the information you have provided to us. We have put in place technology and security policies which are designed to protect the personal information we hold about you. We also follow the security procedures that applicable privacy laws require. These including storing, using and releasing any information you have provided and, as well as measures designed to prevent unauthorised access or use. When you place an order or access your account information, we use a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption which encrypts your information before it is sent to us to protect it from unauthorised use.

**_Why We Link To Other Websites_**

Our online services contain hyperlinks to websites that are owned and operated by other organisations. These websites have their own privacy and cookie policies, and we urge you to read them. They control how your personal information is used when you give it to these other organisations or they collect it with cookies. We do not approve any other websites and we are not responsible for any information, material, products or services that are on or accessible through those websites or for the privacy practices of websites run by other organisations. If you use these other websites you do so at your own risk.

**_Our partnership with Trustpilot for online reviews_**

We link to Trustpilot to enable customers to provide reviews to Trustpilot's review invitation service, which works as follows: The company adds a specific Trustpilot email address on all of the company's order confirmation emails or similar using the blind carbon copy ("Bcc"). From those Bcc emails, Trustpilot automatically retrieves the consumer's information that is needed to send out review invitation emails to consumers on behalf of the company. The only information collected and used by Trustpilot to send out the review invitation emails are the reference number, name and email address of the consumer. The Bcc emails are automatically deleted from Trustpilot's systems after 30 days. Trustpilot processes data on the Esprit Group Of Company's behalf when sending out review invitations to the our customers. The company is the Data Controller and therefore we only act in accordance with the instructions that we receive from the company.

If you click on the link received in the review invitation email you will be redirected to Trustpilot's review page where you must actively accept their terms & conditions and privacy policy before any information relating to your review can be saved. All information collected about the user from this time and going forward is collected by Trustpilot as a Data Controller. The reason why Trustpilot may save this information is for example so that they can contact a customer if his/her review violates Trustpilot's User Guidelines.

**_Testimonials_**

If you give us feedback, we may use it to improve our services and we may publish it online or offline to promote our business and our services. We will ask for your permission before we publish it.

If you wish to submit a comment or feedback on a blog or article featured on our services, we may (but are not obliged to) publish your comment online or offline to promote our business and our services. We will collect your name or username, only part of which may be displayed next to your comments. We will not publish information that may identify any individual, without explicit permission.

**_Mobile services_**

When you request our mobile services, we may keep your mobile phone number, the make and model of your phone, the operating system used by your phone and details of your network operator, and we will link a unique identifier to your mobile phone number. We'll store your device language, app language, country. We need this information in order to provide the features and services enabled through our mobile services and to administer our mobile service. We may also use it for SMS or voice marketing and market research.

**_Social networks_**

If you follow us or interact with us on any of our pages on third party social media platforms, such as Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Pinterest and Google+, information you provide will be subject to the third party's privacy policy, as well as this privacy policy.

back to top
